Thank you for the privilege of calling upon your name.
Follow on the board, it says, in God we trust and we will reaffirm that commitment.
We invite Father, You, to be in our presence tonight.
May You spirit, permit, permit, and in front of Your heart, and mind.
We ask Father and Father that, in God it is filled with such even that we recognize it's a dangerous world.
That we stand on the brink of catastrophe, for Father that power is invested in a few men,
some of which we are gathering, some which may not be a reproffed or you to bring peace,
to our world, to our nation, to our community and to our homes.
I pray Father tonight that Your blessed is meeting.
I thank You Father for each man and woman that sits on this council.
I thank You Father for the contribution of their time and talents, their intelligence, their influence,
and their role in His Father to be used for the betterment of His community.
May Father all the time that's said and done be pleasing in Your sight and may we be blessed.
In the least I had we pray in Christ's name and for His sake. Amen.
Thank You Father.
Can you join me?
I pray to Jesus to the Father of the United States of America.
And to the people who are looking for those just hands, one nation, and a God, the end of His will, with liberty and justice for all.
Thank You Father.
I don't know.
So, there's proper people, there's personal approaches or phone calls.
It's a Ramon.
I'm reluctant to try to answer.
Yeah, I'm trying to answer.
Hi, Ben.
What do I see?
How pleased?
So, I'll wait a minute.
So, let's go back to Ben.
Ben.
And then we have zero.
I just texted Ben to call me.
Yeah, I might say on your phone.
That's right, this is a politician.
So what's happening now?
I don't know what is public input.
And on stage, we'll post some approaches.
Anyone wants to watch it.
To adjust the authority on any of the agenda items.
Anyone that's not ready to escape, or whatever.
And perhaps talk.
There'll be being non-identatives from STEM agenda staff
as recommending item 63 teams for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any.
I don't care.
Those items out.
Motion to approve.
Motion to approve more.
And second.
You call it an eye.
You call it a eye.
OK.
All right.
Thanks.
That takes us to item 11, which is a presentation on the individual.
TC5 and network steady.
And I will.
I will.
Looking for a micolashcraft.
Are you there?
Hi.
Hi, my name is Joe.
Yes, it is.
We've had a little bit of technical shareholders.
But I think we're out of a bunch.
And we are at the appropriate agenda item.
So doing that, I know if you need to make any introductory comments.
You're in the other stock members.
Or I think I don't want to go.
I think very happy to make any introductory comments.
My goal is somebody that I've worked with.
Gosh, Michael, how long have we worked together?
Well, I don't care.
No.
That's it.
I'd like that.
I don't know.
Because people don't eat me usually lose theirs.
You know.
You'll get all right.
My goal.
Michael did a lot of work for the City of Branson on basically survey.
And the ETC Institute and he's in the Kansas City area has done it.
I've worked with him on a number of projects.
I actually wasn't one that hired him in Branson.
But I was one that worked with him.
So he was reputation.
So when we started working with both.
About the possibility of coming into my M on the unique financial condition that Volta's
in.
That yet the desire to come into our community and provide high speed internet.
One of the things we talked about was we really need to do a very good scientific survey that we
can use to rely on for some decisions that we're going to be making.
There's a very important decisions that not only we would be making this a city.
But also the goal would be making as a utility.
We're talking about some multi-million dollar investments that we're wanting to talk about.
So we hired Michael and I want to thank Tyler for basically walking us through this whole program.
And we've done the survey and tonight we're going to be basically giving you the results of the survey.
One thing that I have mentioned to Sheila and bold is that after we get with the survey the question is going to be what's next.
And I think the next step really needs to be this survey needs to go to vote.
And they need to take a look at it and they need to determine based on this survey.
Are they going to proceed?
And if they want to proceed then we need to get.
together, we need to look at how this would work, how it would be financed, and then bring
those opportunities back to you and then make a decision if we're going to move ahead.
So this is basically what we pay for to give you an idea of just what the answer is in regard
to my image interest and high-speed internet.
Michael, is that good for you?
I just want to check out make sure you have the visual city of Miami findings for 2017 survey on your screen.
We do.
Okay.
And being my instructions were to be straightforward on this and go through a pretty good clip,
but I will pause and answer the question that you or the mayor or the council director.
That sounds good.
Very good.
The already disinterductions of retailing institutes.
I will offer one great change with commercial.
That ETC institutes is the largest custom government survey in the recent term in the country.
We do this in every state and 400 to 100 to 30.
But actually it was a very good survey and a little bit surprising.
I will talk about that in just a minute.
We are a part of the agenda.
I am going to talk about the purpose of methodology, some of the major findings, significant results,
and a tool that we use called an IS analysis and then a brief summary.
All the slides that you are going to see in this PowerPoint presentation have already been provided to you in the report.
And actually the report has a lot more information and I am not going to get into all that detail because it is really overwhelming.
Even though it is what I would call good information, it is a lot of information.
But together we are going to remind residents on the use and interest in high speed internet.
The methodology for those of you that don't know, the survey was about 10 minutes in duration.
It was conducted by mail and online and the sample size was 916.
This is part of the most interesting point because Tyler is calling and I talked about this part of this in terms of whether or not people respond to this.
So we guarantee in our contract a minimum of 400 responses which would have given you the same confidence,
whether or not 95 percent.
But the earlier we have been all of the greater.
While we found and I get this credit to your community, they were extremely, and I don't remember the score.
that extremely responsive, I mean we had over 900, actually close to 950 responses, but about
916 horses, they exactly 916 were complete responses, and those people actually build out
the survey responses, beginning to hear very, very good, real briefly.
Can you go back to touch on this, this is Rudy? Can you go back and touch on the stratified
aspect of it? Yes, we wanted to make sure that we got a representation from the various
segments of your community based on the demographic issue you wish to then. I think
that has the gender, number of people in households, and in how much we let the sample size
of the solar water that was easily powered from. Does that make sense, Greer? Yes, thank you,
Greer. Okay, this map where we play shows you the distribution. Now that's 916 dots, because sometimes
people are closely generated, but a good distribution around the city. And the next, the major
findings, I'm going to break it down into these four groups, what was perceived as a service provider
reliability, potential issues of new service options, potential customer parameters, kind of what makes
up those customers, and that's actual with current service providers. So the first one, perceived service
provider reliability, but we did was we asked people to rank have a requirement that the current service
providers were in your community. And I'm not going to note that tomorrow, please, for the
case you have spent your TV, you have selling your dish network. We've plotted this out in terms of reliability
expectations. We're also providing what are called GIS, math, and many of them that we did for each of those
service providers, and I'm not going to go through all of them, but all the information is in your
your report. You see here, and just so you can get a sense of how interpret it is based upon sensitive
blocks, what we do is group responses. And when you see blue, that basically means in that area, whatever
anything, people are running at the area, so that they were using a reliable, if it was yellow,
if it was a reliable, if it was the current standard, and if it's red, it's never, and...
Another thing I would like to tell the one, a little bit more, the one you generally felt that they were using a liable.
But in the drop-down, it was just a liable.
A real high-teen whisperer, not a lot of liable there.
So that's only some concerns with a market liability for some of those service events.
And let's go to detail on the report as you look to those maps that you're with at your leisure.
Next, potential interest in new service options.
One of the things that we did was we wanted to get a sense of if they were to be willing to switch
the TV service providers, what kind of price range would they be interested in considering?
So we asked you that information, so that the meat got better, you had a sense that what those service packages might be competing against.
Why could those describe it?
As he also responds to a bundle service, and if he noticed, almost 69 percent would be likely to be very likely
in describing to an internet service with bundled service, if video were available.
Again, just to show you with the mapping, generally throughout the community they would be likely.
Why could those describe it to a broadband home of a service that's video were available?
So what I mean is that only about 50 percent.
So there are things to be an interest in the more or less packages in the community.
And real quick, we can notice a lot less new for doing something like that.
Special customer parameters, there are three major components, and I'm going to briefly touch on each of those.
Television, phone, and internet of course.
For example, number of operating TV in the home.
In this case, through the federal, or identified, I would mention to you that national matter of my profession.
There's about three hearts, or three TVs in there, excuse me, in the average American home.
So you can follow up online in there.
Next, I'm going to talk about asking about the services.
I have the TV services currently used by YTV networks for entrepreneurs.
top, and we asked about the current service providers, which is probably not just from your general experience that my Amma district to the entire one are the big providers.
If I was a current patient, I would start with information, and then be added to the cost and information to suit what the options are.
I wanted to note that over a third of the respondents said they had over a hundred and ten dollars a month.
And one of the questions that when you go further to me asked, what are your market expectations?
This gives you a sense that people are interested in this service.
The next question has to do with high support services.
And one of the things that I want to point out there is that in the report itself, we do something that's called cost tabs.
And we work it out by, as I mentioned earlier, age of respondents, gender, income, and one of the things that we noticed is that the younger population that has some bias is just kind of their upbringing.
And that's so wireless and self-service is dominated by the youth.
Landline is not so much, which pretty much is going to be a national trend.
So I think that we see here, in terms of household paying for landlines, the younger people are less likely to pay more for landlines,
as well, and I call them as category, the tour residents are merged in landlines generally speaking.
By-line providers, as you can see, it could be called in my amount of internet access.
But this was an interesting statistic to close in the national average, only about 73% of that household had one more than an internet service.
And 84% had a computer.
So you actually, you and I am actually a compare, but in a way to land the call, the larger cities nationwide, and also with a college town.
And I was talking to Mr. Conning earlier, and that may be the importance that India has on my amma as the population there.
So that's only how the interest is internet access.
That could add that providers pay 1 and 18 to the course and types of women that access the
hall right now about half what they call consider high speed service and even when you
have half that have high speed service you have more than half that are interested in this
ultra high speed service.
Number of community devices, one little factboard on that that I found interesting is they
pay five or more and nationally and number is seven but that's on the device that you
recognize and with the use of smart balls and how it ties into the home that a part of living
that number is expected to increase exponentially.
So I just wanted to offer that as perspective.
How much household currently pay for any service, another component as you can see
is US average is about $37.
So your mark is paying a little bit more than that so they definitely have an interest in that service.
That is actually a service for buyers.
Well, we didn't try to get a sense of what the issues you provide, customer,
loyalty and customer interest in Miami and we offered a lot of factors.
I'm not going to go through these.
I will highlight a few of them because I think they would be important to any decisions you make
going forward.
We also do mapping on this and whether there may more maps there's a map for each of those.
There's some of the highlights.
Not a lot of commitment in terms of overall satisfaction, the service or the speed of download
speed.
And even so on this satisfaction, this was a group in the community with the value in that service.
A little time trying to analyze that and as you can see, speed in a service speed,
connectivity, download speed, brain, and reliability and service importance.
Those further we've seen to dominate the discussion.
The full understand that we use a technique called IS analysis.
And I'm not going to get into a lot of detail here because this is in the report.
But when you see an IS analysis of greater than 0.2,
I don't know.
That's not way out of the interest in your community, because what they're telling you, these things are important for people on that side of the side.
And we present this into format first by a numeric rating.
And if you go to the second column for the live importance, that is fact rating, you'll see that you have three that are well over the point to threshold.
And the high priority about the live importance on my accent, that's really very close. It's a high priority item.
And what I'm looking for is graphed out for us, who are a little picture orders.
It's those little points that are on the right hand side of that chart.
And down the bottom there is value you receive.
I don't know if you can see my cursor down here, value you received for your service.
Definitely have some interest in having improved value for that reliability, and that speed and access.
Expectations and some service levels are switching from a current service provider to a consider.
A lot of interest there, expectations very high speed, reliable service is an important issue for the community at large.
We also run it down because the community, by one of my talk about this, are that the impact in my have on not just column use for also office use and the team.
Really pass about 79% of the whole users were interested in almost 75% of three quarters of those people who work out in home and office.
Who would be interested in the service to do work from home, where they start out on a particular activities or current businesses.
And we break it out, so you get an understanding.
See all the blue there, high interest across the community for the premium service.
Actually, the particular thing is now one pocket for the high speed internet office and the work.
In summary, I will offer, quite honestly, that your community, based on this survey and my reviewer survey, I was suggest, are very well engaged.
They are interested in this issue, and they think it's important.
And they have a high degree of interest.
Community live, it's not just in a pocket or two, although if the younger you are, the more attentive.
or the development of reliable, affordable, and high-speed internet.
And that's all I've got to say.
Good job. Any questions for Michael?
No, no, no. I don't mind. I don't.
Do any of this take on the line, as we can do some of this.
I think if Michael is just basically giving us the results of the survey.
So if you have any questions about that, otherwise as I said,
this is going to be something for her, she let her staff to take a hard look at
and then get back with us, and then we'll start reporting to you about any agreements we might have
with both to be able to bring them into town.
But I think this is the foundation we were looking for.
She, I don't know if you might want to say anything.
Yes, I mean, this is very exciting and congratulations on the survey.
The response was phenomenal.
And when we did that our survey at both,
we were just as amazed at the turnover of applications
and surveys whenever we got it back.
The interest was very high.
Something that we have been able to maybe do over this past year.
We've been discussing with the city about the opportunity of possibly
bringing our gigabit network into your city.
But during this time, we've also been building out our own network.
We've been able to see and you've been able to probably hear from our residences
and our businesses, all of the neat things that's brought to them.
And how well our services are being received.
We've got a very robust network.
It's a top of a line in the state of the art network.
We'd love the opportunity.
Today we're going to visit with the city here in Dean and make sure that everything
as far as the numbers will work.
But it's very exciting.
We've seen everything from hundreds of new jobs come to play.
Businesses expanding because of the network.
So yeah, it's a great thing I'm looking forward to working with you guys.
Thank we have several both customers sitting in the audience.
Oh, okay.
Great.
That's good to know.
So we're going to have to make a little stand at this point.
I've got one.
Mr. Alley Scott, there's this.
The number one the screen is up contact.
You know, basically, of course, in the little contact.
Yeah, that's that's my personal information.
I hope you can read the mail at Michael.
And you need that second L in there.
The other Michael Alley Scott is not real polite if you contact me.
We'll keep that in mind, even.
Any other questions for mine?
Thank you.
Michael, I just want to thank you to, you know, for us kind of doing this.
We all look to each other going, how do we do this and I'm glad you were a resource for us. I'd greatly appreciate it. Thank you very much Michael
Great job it and
I would have a great job
I really appreciate working with him. So I wish you all all
You have a lot of your quite honestly that's just me personally speaking
All right, thank you again. Bye. Bye. Bye. Bye. Okay. Thank you. Bye. Bye. Bye
Okay, so before we move to item 12, so if we've
Confirm the sort of the back of the server and we've heard from Sheila is there any other conversation
We need to have around this issue tonight being not tonight, but I do think that next week
We're going to be talking about rights
That's kind of picking that conversation up again and I think that we're probably going to want to talk to the council about if we proceed with this
How we may want to do this with this right study that we're talking about and some of the bond issues
I just I don't want to tell a graph too much. I think this is something we need to think about but you might remember originally
We kind of we've saved a chunk of money thinking that this might be coming up. Well, with this survey and also the fact that
You know, this is supposed to be the backbone of a smart grid system for my Emma
If we can get this up and running as quickly as possible
I think we need to be able to move quickly on the smart grid system as well. That's what we're putting our money into
And then the fringe benefit of course then is that our citizens will have access to bold
So I think we need to factor this into our our rate study that we're going to be talking about next week
So I just wanted to kind of get you ready for that and that discussion
But if our citizens really want this
I think it's going to be money lost now and so she know if you'd come back up
Please, I'm starting not going to hold you to a number, but you saw the three numbers on the screen
I think the highest one was 83 99
There was a 63 and a 49
We've almost fed in the parameters we're reading the range it for your current customers outside of this area for that level of service
So yeah, okay, it's right there
Absolutely
Okay, thank you
Thanks, you
Any other questions on that item?
Okay, we're going to move to item 12 which is to a really build for born a water line and we'll show we've worked to my
And sons construction of a pilot. Yes, I'm such an advocate for you is
Is the award mom and sons the bid for we're boring underneath the new show. We're the sort of new about water line that's on the current 125 bridge and put it underneath the river
We know a lot in the future is going to be redacking that bridge
So we would be putting it back on the bridge versus putting it into the river and we came up with the best idea was put more in under the river
So we had the design done and we'd put it out for bid and to not before you're the the five bids that we have
In mom and sons was a lowest
We're very out of it, Tom.
They're out of high school at Lama.
You're comfortable with their level of experience.
You're so Sean, Sean McConaughey from Olsen.
We actually had a conference call with them on Thursday.
They actually have a...
Well, would you say it premieres coming down with a boring unit
about their brand new boring unit?
And they're actually going to demo it for them on this board.
So I guess it's a new developed boring unit
and they think they won't be a problem.
So they're very excited about it.
I didn't see any problem, did you, Sean?
No, I did.
Okay.
You guys are getting a really good deal on this.
Do we have a motion to approve the contract with mom and son?
We did more.
And a second.
I'll second it.
We'll call.
Tom, sir.
Lewis, hi.
Weston.
Hi.
I don't know.
Taylor's new business.
Any new business dean or anyone?
Not for the year order.
I'm 15.
Staff report.
Hey, ready.
We did it.
The first one was awarded the bid and the second one was to approve their contract.
Well, the current.
13.
So contract.
Okay, sir.
Okay.
My apologies.
I am 13.
So the item 12 was for awarding the bid.
And I actually took those out of order because I said I approved the contract.
So we're not going to approve the reward bid.
Do we have a motion to approve item 12?
And then a second.
No second.
We're all.
Weston.
Hi.
Johnson.
Lewis, hi.
And now we're going to do 13 over.
Just to make sure that the bid is comfortable with that.
I'd like the most to approve item 13.
Do we have a second?
No.
Paul, please.
Hi.
Lewis, hi.
Johnson.
Thank you.
Yep.
All right.
14.
We talked about 15.
We talked about 16.
velocmentesubple.
No.
We didn't want to know.
15.
13.
fragments for this, for the authority.
30.
ww.
11 deportation.
115.
We Premier.
10.
Now the summit will hall please.
quotation.
9.
170.
20.
deter number.
conception.
14.
10.